import 'package:quiz_app_tutorial/models/question.dart';

const List<Question> questions = [
  Question(
    question: '1. Who is the last prophet in Islam?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Prophet Muhammad (PBUH)',
      'b) Prophet Isa (Jesus)',
      'c) Prophet Musa (Moses)',
      'd) Prophet Ibrahim (Abraham)',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '2. What is the holy book of Islam?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Quran',
      'b) Bible',
      'c) Torah',
      'd) Guru Granth Sahib',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '3. In which month do Muslims fast from sunrise to sunset?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Rajab',
      'b) Shawwal',
      'c) Ramadan',
      'd) Dhu al-Hijjah',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '4. What is the pilgrimage to Mecca called in Islam?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Hajj',
      'b) Umrah',
      'c) Ziyarat',
      'd) Tawaf',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '5. How many pillars of Islam are there?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 3,
    options: [
      'a) 2',
      'b) 4',
      'c) 5',
      'd) 6',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '6. What is the Islamic declaration of faith?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Shahada',
      'b) Tawhid',
      'c) Takbir',
      'd) Salah',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '7. Which direction do Muslims face when they pray?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Kaaba in Mecca',
      'b) Al-Aqsa Mosque in Jerusalem',
      'c) Mount Uhud in Medina',
      'd) The North Star',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '8. How many days does the Hajj pilgrimage last?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) 1 day',
      'b) 7 days',
      'c) 5 days',
      'd) 10 days',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '9. Who is considered the first Caliph in Islam?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) Abu Bakr',
      'b) Umar ibn Al-Khattab',
      'c) Ali ibn Abi Talib',
      'd) Uthman ibn Affan',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '10. What is the annual charity giving required in Islam?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Zakat al-Fitr',
      'b) Zakat al-Mal',
      'c) Zakat al-Qurbani',
      'd) Zakat al-Sadaqah',
    ],
  ),
];
